Some other points, finer points I want to make about adjustable seating and cushioning for people with disabilities is again, I want to make the point that if you're helping somebody with a spinal cord injury to really make sure the seating is as comfortable as possible.
You or I, who might not have a spinal cord injury, can usually re-adjust ourselves in our canoe seats as often as possible.
Sometimes, if you're ever sitting at a desk, you'll notice yourself shifting around a lot.
That's because we're trying to aleve pressure sores.
However, people with spinal cord injuries don't always feel that they need to readjust themselves to aleve those press pressure sores.
So what I like to do is, if somebody's coming canoeing with me that ha, that is in a wheelchair, I always like to look at their wheelchair and ask them what is, what kind of cushioning support do you need?
Always ask your participant.
It's not rude to ask.
It's very respectful, and it gives you a good insight as to the needs that they'll need for canoeing or rafting, or just sort of any type of adaptable equipment.
So, always look at their cushioning, and all also for, as far as back support; whether you're going to need the patio chair or the Chosen Valley chair.
Again, look at a participant's wheelchair.
Some participants use manual wheelchairs.
Maybe they have a lower level spinal cord injury; in which case, maybe the patio chair is great for them.
Maybe there might be other people that use a power wheelchair that usually has a higher back and needs a little bit more support, so maybe the Chosen Valley canoe seat would be great for them.
Again, just look at their wheelchairs, and sort of assess what sort of cushioning and back support their need, and then also ask your participant, what kind of support do you need?
It's very respectful to ask that question, and a lot of times the participants; they've been in similar situations before, and so they know what's, what works best for them.
So just always, you know, ask questions, and assess based off of systems that are already set up in place.